## **BRET ROBINSON**

redbackinc@gmail.com (403) 617-5935

## Full Stack Developer

## **Summary**

IT professional with experience in diverse industries including digital media, Oil & Gas and public sector. Strong knowledge of multiple programming languages including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Perl and Linux shells. I also have a good understanding of React, React Native, Nodejs, Express and AWS. RESTful APIs were created for my last two projects - a Movie Warning Database and an Artisans' Selling site. I have practical knowledge of the Agile software development processes and write my code using software development best practices. Known for my reliability, honesty, integrity and technical knowledge. I am a lifelong learner and am always excited to learn new technologies.

## **Core Strengths**

- Software Development Lifecycle
- Linux Administration
- Scripting Languages

- Technical Knowledge
- Infrastructure & Application Knowledge
- Communications and Interpersonal Skill

## **Relevant Experience**

### <u>Development/Linux Administration/Technical Support</u>

- Wrote mobile phone app using React Native for an Artisans' selling site.
- Used the full MERN stack to create a Movie Warning database. The basic movie metadata was gathered using the IMDB api and the warnings were crowdsourced.
- Created an automatic deployment method using GitHub and Heroku.
- Wrote RESTful APIs used with MongoDB and MySQL databases.
- Rewrite and migrate all middleware administrative scripts used in the Red Hat and SUSE WebSphere MQ environments. Implement a source control system using Git and create a repeatable deployment process using TeamCity and Artifactory.
- Wrote custom deployment scripts to automate OS upgrades and patches to remote servers.
- Developed scripts to report on current server states including all hardware and OS configuration information.
- Wrote scripts to scan and monitor servers and workstations for security vulnerabilities and alert administrators
  of any anomalies found. Alerts sent were both emails and SNMP messages.
- Used build and compile tools like gcc and make to build and deploy source code on multiple platforms.
- Extensive experience using Perl to write scripts ranging from very simple to complex including the use of recursive code, Perl TK and manipulating databases.

#### **Full Stack Developer**

EvolveU, Calgary, Alta

2020 - 2021

- Attended a six-month project-based course learning all parts of the stack both front-end and back-end. All
  of the three projects used GitHub for the source repository.
- Project one involved a static website using HTML and CSS.
- Project two was a Movie Warning site using the full MERN stack.
- Project three was a mobile app that included the use of React, React Native, Material UI, Nodejs, Express, MySQL, AWS and Heroku.

Bret Robinson Mobile: 403-617-5935 Email: redbackinc@gmail.com

#### Middleware Support

Canadian Pacific Railway, Calgary, Alta

• Responsible for successful completion of the Source Control and Deployment project for the middleware team. Included creating coding standards, version control repository and repeatable deployment process.

• Involved with project to migrate middleware administrative scripts to four new business environments. Purpose of project is to standardize coding methods, version control and a repeatable deployment process. Git (Bitbucket) was used for version control and TeamCity and Artifactory were used for the deployment process. All scripts migrated were written in ksh and are used for the support of WebSphere MQ.

#### Sabbatical/Education

Calgary, Alta 2016 – 2018

- Time spent completing projects after building my own house. Personal projects that were able to be completed due to other priorities in the past.
- Completed on-line courses related to Programming, Databases, Project Management and Photography.

### **Senior Business Systems Analyst**

Lightstream Resources (now Ridgeback Resources), Calgary, Alta

2013 - 2016

2019

 Analyst responsible for the GG&E application portfolio for Lightstream on both Linux and Windows environments. Liaison between the business and IT to build, test and deliver solutions.

### **Senior Application Support Analyst**

Encana Corporation, Calgary, Alta

2003 - 2012

- Migration of application and user environments to Linux based server and workstation environments. The migration was from Solaris machines to Red Hat.
- Provided support for the GG&E application suite for on-shore business units.
- Accountable for all application upgrades and data migration between versions.

#### **Technical Skills**

**Technologies:** AWS, Azure, VirtualBox, React, React Native, Nodejs, Express, Mongoose, Heroku **Software:** GitHub/GitBucket, Jest, JIRA, MS Project, MS Office, MS Visio, MS Access, MS

SharePoint, TeamCity, Artifactory, RSpec, Ruby on Rails, Apache, phpBB

Apps Supported: WebSphere MQ, SeisWare, Accumap, geoSCOUT, Petrel, GeoFrame, Hampson-Russell,

Transform, Earth Vision, Paradigm suite (SeisX, Geolog, VoxelGeo), CMG suite, IHS

Harmony, Techlog, AFE Navigator, interCalm, Mosaic and OpenSpirit

**Databases:** MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server, Sybase

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Perl, Korn shell, bash, Bourne shell, PowerShell, C shell, C, Java

O/S: Linux, Solaris, AIX, Windows, Mac OS X Networking: TCP/IP, DNS, LDAP, NFS, SMTP, SNMP

Bret Robinson Mobile: 403-617-5935 Email: redbackinc@gmail.com

# **Education and Training**

• EvolveU: Full Stack Developer Training

**EvolveU** 

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals

Microsoft

• Microsoft Certified: Azure Administrator Associate - in progress

Microsoft

• Applied Project Management Certificate of Achievement

Southern Alberta Institute of Technology

• ITIL Foundation

Service Management Art

• Windows Server 2012: Installation and Configuration

Lynda.com

• SQL Essential Training

Lynda.com

• Programming Foundations: Databases

Lynda.com

• Ruby on Rails Developer

Lynda.com

• Java Programming

University of Calgary

• Diploma of Technology, Computer Systems

British Columbia Institute of Technology

Bret Robinson Mobile: 403-617-5935 Email: redbackinc@gmail.com